This beginner Pilates Exercise is called the double leg stretch.
This is the second exercise part of what we called the Five Abs series.
So really concentrate on pulling your abdominal muscles and focus on your breath.
Come on down to the mat and bring your knees in towards your chest, lifting your head and shoulders up off the mat.
Gently place your hands on the outside of your lower legs and we're going to extend the arms and the legs in opposition.
When you extend your legs, pull your legs into a Pilates dance, which means your heels are together and your toes are out like a V. Keep the small of your back down to the mat.
And then circle your arms around and bring your knees into your chest.
So inhale as you open, exhale bring your knees in.
Inhale, extend; exhale, bring it in.
Straight arms over head, then circle around.
Now, where do you want to look?
You want to look towards your legs, try to avoid looking up towards the ceiling.
You want to really protect that neck. So looking forward, contracting those abs. Perform about eight to ten reps. And that is your double leg stretch.